Timothy Morrise

Full Stack Web Developer looking to apply skills in Javascript/Node.js Salt Lake City, UT 84103 (801) 560-6195



Utmorrise.surge.sh 🖾 timothy.morrise@gmail.com 🕻 🕽 /timothymorrise 📗 🖍 /timothy-morrise





PROJECTS

Screaming At Awards Shows — Full Stack CRUD Website

An app to generate text for a personal ballot for different Film and TV Awards Shows. Uses React/Redux for front-end, pulling from a local Restful API for the Award Show data built with Express and MonogoDB.

Marquee Salad — 'Nilla Javascript Single Page Site

A minimalist web page that helps theater operators know which letters to pull when changing their marquees. Built using "vanilla" Javascript

Boy Counter Experience — *Personal Site that uses the Youtube API*

A personal site I built using the Youtube API to populate a page with videos from the web series "Monster Factory." It manages personal data using React/Redux and **Flexbox** to create a pseudo-blog feed design and navigation.

EXPERIENCE

Salt Lake Film Society, Salt Lake City, UT — Front of House Staff/Development Assistant

MAY 2015 - PRESENT

- Trained team of 15+ Front of House staff on Union Procedures and Practices, and trained and managed team of 10+ volunteers on donor management in company database
- CoAuthored Collective Bargaining Agreement while working on contract committee of 8 people to provide wage parity and industry standard practices to Front of House Staff
- Saved the nonprofit \$1000, initialized a retention program to track inventory
- Managed regular high pressure customer loads of up to a rate of 1500/hour

Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, Salt Lake City, UT — Young Church Service Missionary

APRIL 2014 - APRIL 2016

- Marathon tested 1000 digital media per hour assets during peak QC hours
- Product tested database and UI interface for Digital Media QC Programs
- Researched, presented and piloted a program for QC Mobile testing
- Quality Checked a variety of high volume websites organized in a task manager

Workforce QA, Salt Lake City, UT — Medical Review Officer Assistant

IUNE 2013 - MAY 2014

- Reviewed thousands of documents for compliance standards
- Performed routine indexing and data entry
- Operated phone lines and directed calls for Medical Review processes

SKILLS

- Front End
 - Javascript
 - React
 - o HTML 5
 - **CSS**
- Back End
 - Node.js
 - **Express**
 - Mongo
 - MongoDB
- Other Skills
 - Git
 - ISON
 - Adobe Premiere
 - Adobe Audition
 - o AV Technician
 - **Public Speaking**

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Javascript Web Development V School 2018

IATSE Live Event Technician Certification 2019

BS Economics Southern Utah University 2012